919.889.2401 :: adam.p.barrett@gmail.com :: ab75173.github.io

About

I am a Developer who specializes in WordPress and utilizes Bootstrap for media queries and Grunt for task automation. I have exposure to WP-CLI, Salesforce, social media API's, Ruby on Rails and various front end JavaScript libraries.

Experience

Developer

agencyQ, Washington, DC, March 2015 - September 2015

Contributed to various open-source projects and served as the lead developer on WordPress builds. Constructed AJAX page load for custom fields, developed search index pages, architected multilingual websites, and created client-to-user chat functionality.

Developer

VOX Global, Washington, DC, November 2014 - February 2015

Served as a developer for creating IE8+ compatible Adobe CQ page templates and created WordPress themes from Photoshop design mockups. Assisted with front end development of in-house software products for Fortune 100 clients.

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly, Washington, DC, April 2014 - July 2014

Full stack web development program focused on common best practices in objectoriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development. Developed a portfolio of individually focused and collaboratively focused projects.

Technology Project Associate

Center for Shared Services, Arlington, VA, September 2012 - February 2014 Maximized available IT and web services to create value in client solutions. Excelled in preventative maintenance in servicing both the internal and external customers. Managed web application projects for internal and external clients. Designed and developed websites for clients advocating free market principles. Utilized FormAssembly and Salesforce to create database contacts for organizations. Created visuals for social media outlets, print publications, and email campaigns.

Web & IT Associate

Competitive Enterprise Institute, Washington, DC, March 2012 - September 2012 Managed Facebook and Twitter accounts, edited websites and blogs, monitored web activity, and created visuals. Served as the IT Help Desk liaison, helped troubleshoot Microsoft Windows, installed hardware and software, built and refurbished computers, acted as the point-of-contact for staff with IT needs and vendors, and tracked IT inventory.

Education

Appalachian State University, Boone, NC, May 2010 Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Economics